Guide to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello RG.006
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series IV: Organizations, 10
  - Subseries D: New York City Partnership, 1979-1995; 1911
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1982-1983; 1914 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1984-1987; 1915 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1988; 1916 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1989 May-June 14; 1917 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1989 June 19-December; 1918 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1990; 1919 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1991; 1920 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, 1992-1995; 1921 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - NYC Partnership – Miscellaneous, Undated; 1922 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - NYC Partnership - Hi-Tech Committee, 1988-1990; Undated; 1923 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - NYC Partnership - BMD Trade Mission - Photographs, 1982 June; 1924 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - NYC Partnership – Technology Executive Council, 1990-1991; 1925 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Subseries E: North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 19
    - Ankara, 1994 June; 1098 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Ankara Program, 1994; 1106 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Ankara, Turkey - Bios, 1993 December-1994 October; 1116 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Aytmatov, Dr. Ilgiz, 1994 March; 1107 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Belarus, 1994 April; 1072 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Brill, Yvonne C., 1994 March-June; 1073 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Budget, 1993 December-1996 February; 1085 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Bugliarello, Virginia, 1994 June; 1097 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Cadiou, Dr. Jean, 1993 September-1994 June; 1074 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Carroll, William, 1994 January-June; 1105 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Circular, 1994 June-July; 1115 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence - Follow-ups, 1994 February; 1102 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - David, Dr. Ed, 1993 September-1994 April; 1075 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - DiCataldo, Vincenzo, 1994 April; 1076 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Dineen, Dr. Gerald P., 1993 September-1994 March; 1077 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Erhan, Dr. Sevim, 1994 April; 1078 (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Fabian, John M., 1993 July-1994 February; 1079 (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - Forsen, Dr. Harold K., 1994 January-February; 1080 (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - Gage, Carl, 1994 March-April; 1081 (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Gordos, Dr. Geza, 1993 October -1994 June; 1082 (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - Greece, 1986 July -1990 September; 1121 (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - Greece, 1990 February-April; 1122 (Box 35, Folder 39)
    - Greece, 1992 July; 1141 (Box 35, Folder 40)
    - Greece, 1995 July-August; 1084 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Greek Polyblend, 1995 October, 1996 March; 1112 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Hemily, Philip W., 1993 October-1994 April; 1088 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Hertlein, Dr. H.P., 1994 June; 1109 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Jubier, Alain H., 1993 September-1994 June; 1110 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Kabanov, Victor A., 1993 June-1994 February; 1083 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Kazakhstan, 1993 September-1994 February; 1111 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Kazakhstan Course, 1995 February; 1114 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Kluwer Academic Publishers, 1994 January-1996 August; 1086 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Master, 1993 April-December; 1101; ` (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Master, 1993 March-1994 July; 1064 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1989 May-December; 1123 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990 February-November; 1124 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990 December; 1125 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991 March-April; 1126 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992 February-June; 1127 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1993 January-November; 1128 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994 January-June; 1129 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994 July; 1130 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994 August-November; 1131 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994 December; 1142 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995 January-December; 1132 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1996 April-1997 April; 1136 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated; 1133 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Murino, Teresa, 1994 May-July; 1087 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Nalecz, Dr. Maciej, 1993 September-1994 March; 1103 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Nesvetailov, Dr. Gennady, 1994 April; 1104 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1985 February, 1993 January-November; 1120 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Ney, Andrew L. Esq., 1993 November; 1108 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - NSF, 1993 January-1994 July; 1100 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Poholkov, Yuri Petrovich, 1993 September-1994 May; 1119 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Rabkin, Professor Yakov M., 1993 November-1994 June; 1065 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Radosevic, Dr. Slavo, 1994 March-September; 1117 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Rambaut, Dr. Paul, 1994 June; 1066 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Russia, 1993 September-October; 1099 (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - Russian Space Agency, 1994 February-June; 1118 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Sahin, Dr. Faith, 1994 April; 1089 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Salakhitdinov, Professor M.S., 1994 January-April; 1068 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Salmon, William C., 1994 April-June; 1069 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Schillinger, Dr. George, 1994 May; 1090 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Schweitzer, Glenn, 1994 January-April; 1091 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Science for Stability Program, 1993 April-December; 4639 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Science for Stability Program, 1994 January-December; 1134 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Science for Stability Program - Program proposals, 1992; 1139 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Science for Stability Program – Program proposals, 1994; 1135 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Sherwood, Robert M., 1994 July; 1067 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Spiro, Jody, 1994 March-May; 1092 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Sultangazin, Dr. Omirzak Makhmutovich, 1994 March-June; 1070 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Syrbe, Dr. M., 1993 September; 1093 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Tishkov, Dr. K., 1994 April; 1071 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - TU-Black Sea, 1993 May; 1140 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - TU-Language Program, 1995 April-May; 1113 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Turkey, 1993 September-August; 1137 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Turkey, 1993 September-August; 1138 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Ukraine, 1993 October-1994 May; 1094 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - U.S. Embassies / Former USSR, 1994 May-June; 1062 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Vance, Elsie, 1994 March-April; 1095 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Warnecke, Dr. Ing. Hans Jurgen, 1994 March-July; 1063 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Zinberg, Dr. Dorothy, 1994 March-June; 1096 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Suberies F: Sigma Xi: The Scientific Research Society, 17
    - Sigma Xi - Miscellaneous, 1991 April-November; 1263 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Sigma Xi - Miscellaneous, 1992 January-June; 1264 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Sigma Xi - Miscellaneous, 1992 July-September; 1265 (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Sigma Xi - Miscellaneous, 1992 October-December; 1266 (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Sigma Xi - Miscellaneous, 1993 January-December; 1267 (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Sigma Xi - Miscellaneous, 1994 January-April; 1268 (Box 37, Folder 30)
    - Sigma Xi - Miscellaneous, Undated; 1269 (Box 37, Folder 31)
    - Sigma Xi - Ad Hoc Committee, 1992 August, 1993 January; 1270 (Box 37, Folder 32)
    - Sigma Xi - Capital Campaign, 1992 May-August; 1271 (Box 37, Folder 33)
    - Sigma Xi - Conference, 1991 November-1992 March; 1272 (Box 37, Folder 34)
    - Sigma Xi - Correspondence, 1992 June-September; 1273 (Box 37, Folder 35)
    - Sigma Xi - Correspondence, 1992 October; 1274 (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - Sigma Xi - Executive Committee, 1992 February 24; 1275 (Box 37, Folder 37)
    - Sigma Xi - Thomas F. Malone, 1992 October-December; 1276 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Subseries G: Teagle Foundation, 1986-1993; 1928
    - Teagle Foundation – Board Meetings, 1986 February-May, 1993 February; 1929 (Box 37, Folder 39)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1983 October-1987 December; 1930 (Box 37, Folder 40)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1988 February-September; 1931 (Box 37, Folder 41)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1988 October-December; 1932 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1989; 1933 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1990 January-April; 1934 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1990 May-December; 1935 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1991 January-February; 1936 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1991 April-December; 1937 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Teagle Foundation – Miscellaneous, 1992; Undated; 1938 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Subseries H: Miscellaneous, 1978-1995; 1939
    - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA) – Annual Meeting Panel, 1987 February-April; 1940 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Association of Independent Technological University (AITU), 1992-1993; 1941 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Board of Visitors – Duke University, 1992-1994; 1942 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Board of Overseers – School of Engineering and Applied Sciences - University of Pennsylvania, 1992 July -1994 March; 1943 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce – Business-Education Committee, 1987 March-1988 November; 1944 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Comtech (Telecommunications Corp.), 1989, 1993; Undated; 1945 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Egypt-U.S. Joint Consultative Council for Applied Science and Technology Research, 1978 May; 1946 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Financial Services Technology Consortium (FinTech) – Miscellaneous, Handwritten notes, 1990-1993; 1947 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Lord Corporation, 1993-1994; 1948 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Marconi International Fellowship – Promotional Material, Undated; 1949 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Mayor's Award for Science & Technology – RESTRICT, 1993 May-September; 1950 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Mayor's Commission for Science and Technology, 1989 December; 1967 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - M.I.T. Alumni Association, 1993; 1952 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - National Academic of Sciences (NAS) - Proposed articles, Drafts - 1 - RESTRICT, 1980; 1953 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - NAS - Proposed articles, Drafts - 2 - RESTRICT, 1980; 1954 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - NAS - Proposed articles, Drafts - 3 - RESTRICT, 1980; 1955 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - National Medal of Technology - Nomination Committee, 1989 July-1991 February; 1957 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - National Medal of Technology - Nomination Committee Forms, 1990-1991; 5768 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - NRC (National Research Council), 1992; 1958 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - NRC, 1993-1994; 1959 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - National Science Foundation, 1990, 1994; 1960 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity, 1976; 4504 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Regional Plan Association, 1992 July-1994 March; 1961 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - United Nations – World Engineering Partnership for Sustainable Development (WEPSD), 1993 April; 1962 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - United Nations - Commission on Science and Technology – Gender Working Group, 1994 November-December; 1963 (Box 38, Folder 32)
- Series V: Speeches & Symposia, 9
  This series contains transcripts and notes from speeches and lectures given by George Bugliarello at national and international conferences, symposiums and other events.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Speeches, 2080
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974; 976 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1974; 1976; 977 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1977 January-November; 1007 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1978 March-October; 1009 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1979 March-September; 1011 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1980 February-March; 1012 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1980 April-October; 1014 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1981 December; Undated; 1015 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1981 December; Undated; 1594 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1982; 1016 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1983; 1017 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1984 February-December; 1019 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1985 May-December; 1021 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1986 February-December; 1028 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1987 February-November; Undated; 1037 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1988 February-December; 1039 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1989 January-November; 1040 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1990 February-March; 1041 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1990 May-July; 1042 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1990 August-November; 1043 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1991; 1044 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1992; 1047 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1993 February-October; 1056 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, Undated; 1059 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Technology and Education" – 9th World Conference of Correspondence Education – Airlie House, VA, 1972 May; 1842 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "University Industry Interaction" – Long Island Association, 1975 January 15; 978 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Industry- University Interaction is Good for Business" – Advancement for Commerce and Industry, 1975 January 15; 1843 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Othmer, Don, 1975 February 1; 979 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Biological Organisms, Social Organisms and Machines" – Monmouth Junior Science Symposium, 1975 March 6; 980 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "The Development of Technology-Based Industry on Long Island – Conference at Polytechnic Institute of New York At Farmingdale, 1975 May 10; 982 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - WQXR Statement - Long Island, NY, 1975 June 3; 983 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - "Technology Units in City Government "– New York State Charter Revision Commission, 1975 June 16; 984 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "Remarks at University of the International Association of Universities – Moscow University, 1975 August 21; 985 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Speech to the Faculty – Polytechnic University, 1975 September; 986 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Testimony at Hearing on New York State Economic Redevelopment Authority Act – World Trade Center, 1975 September 30; 988 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "Universities of the Community in the United States and the Socialist Countries – University of Illinois at Urbana, 1975 October 10; 989 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Bern Dibner Tribute, 1975 October 21; 991 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - "L'Universita, La Facolta' Di Ingegniria E La Comunita", 1975 December 17; 992 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - "American Ingenuity At the Bicentennial" – Joint Meeting of the New York City Chapter of the National Society of Professional Engineers and the New York City Section of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers – Engineers Club, New York City, 1976 February; 1844 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - "Coating Technology – An Outsider's View of the Industry" – St. Louis, Missouri, 1976 February; 994 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Administrative Leadership, 1976 February 3; 996 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Introductory Remarks – Address by Senator Henry Jackson – Long Island, New York, 1976 March 26; 997 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - "Technology and the Corporation" – Engineer's Day, Lord Corporation, 1976 April; 1000 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - "Technology, Values, and Engineering Systems" – Symposium on Technology and the Spirit of Man – University of Iowa, 1976 April 19; 998 (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - Welcome Speech – Microwave Research Institute (MRI), 1976 April 20; 999 (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - "Perspectives in Biomechanics Research and Education Over the Past Ten Years" - Waterloo, Canada, 1976 May 26; 1001 (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - Faculty & Corporation Meeting, 1976 June; 1002 (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - Commencement Address – Polytechnic Institute of New York - Carnegie Hall, 1976 June 2; 1003 (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York at Farmingdale – Long Island, New York, 1976 July 13; 1004 (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - Corporation Meeting, 1976 October 13; 1005 (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - Remarks on the Occasion of a Luncheon in Honor of Senator James Buckley – Farmingdale, Long Island, NY, 1976 October 14; 1845 (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - Gruman Hall Dedication, 1976 December 23; 1006 (Box 40, Folder 33)
    - "We Must Develop a Stronger Technological Base for Long Island" – World Gateway Executive Forum Breakfast, 1977 August 17; 1008 (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - "The Problem of Industry-University Interaction" – Conference on Engineering and Science Research for Industrial Development" – Easton, MA, 1977 October 3-7; 1846 (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - "The New Engineering Ethics" – Rochester, New York, 1978 June 5; 1847 (Box 40, Folder 36)
    - "The Paint and Coating Industry Hypothesis for the Future" - Science of Organic Coatings Conference – Kent State University, 1978 June 20-22; 1848 (Box 40, Folder 37)
    - "Graduate Programs in Engineering and our National Needs" – Engineering Foundation Conference – Henniker, New Hampshire, 1978 July 11; 1849 (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - "For a Stronger Industry-University Interaction" – Key Note, Conference on Mechanisms of University-Industry Interaction – Reston, Virginia, 1978 December 7; 1850 (Box 40, Folder 39)
    - "A Note on Orientation and Curriculum for Technological Education in Nigeria", 1979 April 10; 1851 (Box 40, Folder 40)
    - Radio and Television, 1979-1980; 1010 (Box 40, Folder 41)
    - College Presidents' Panel, "Long Island Colleges Move to Meet Long Island's Growing Technology Education Needs" - Long Island Forum for Technology Breakfast, 1984 September 13; 1020 (Box 40, Folder 42)
    - "Technology and the Environment" – International Conference "Man's Role in Changing the Global Environment" - Venice, Italy, 1985 October 22; 1018 (Box 40, Folder 43)
    - "University and the Small Entrepreneur" –Peat Marwick, Venture Capital Group, 1985 October; 1022 (Box 40, Folder 44)
    - Chemistry Symposium, 1985 November 22; 1024 (Box 40, Folder 45)
    - "Science and Technology and Religion" - Religion in America - Princeton Club, New York, New York, 1985 December 3; 2018 (Box 40, Folder 46)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, 1986; 1025 (Box 40, Folder 47)
    - "National Center for Space Electronics – Proposal, 1986 January; 1026 (Box 40, Folder 48)
    - Colleges and Universities Versus Schools: Shall The Twins Meet?" – National Technology Literacy Conference – Baltimore, Maryland, 1986 February 16; 1027 (Box 40, Folder 49)
    - Weber Dedication, 1986 March; 1029 (Box 40, Folder 50)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York at Westchester Dinner Speech – John R. Opel, 1986 May; 1030 (Box 40, Folder 51)
    - "Research & Development for Macroprojects" – Symposium on Governmental Management of Technological Change, 1986 May 30; 1031 (Box 40, Folder 52)
    - "Fluid Mechanics in Civil Engineering: The Crisis and the Opportunity" – Dinner Address, ASCE Special Conference on Advancements in Aerodynamics, Fluid Mechanics and Hydraulics – Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1986 June 4; 1033 (Box 40, Folder 53)
    - Minneapolis Speech Notes (see folder 53), undated; 7160 (Box 40, Folder 54)
    - Sal Nuzzo Dinner – Long Island, NY, 1986 September; 1034 (Box 40, Folder 55)
    - "Business, Industry and the University" – Erie, Pennsylvania, 1986 October; 1035 (Box 40, Folder 56)
    - Board Meeting / Retreat Address, 1986 October 30-November 1; 1036 (Box 40, Folder 57)
    - "Lo Spazio Dell'ingegneria Nella Scienza Moderna" Conference – Torino, Italy, 1987 October; 1038 (Box 40, Folder 58)
    - "The Future of Science" – Achievement Rewards for College Scientists (ARCS) – Hotel Pierre, New York City, 1991 May 15; 1852 (Box 40, Folder 59)
    - Third International Conference on Management of Technology – University of Miami, 1992 February 17-21; 1853 (Box 40, Folder 60)
    - "Technology Transfer: A Socio-Technological Paradigm" – Presentation at the Symposium on Development and Transfer of Industry Technology – 20th Anniversary Celebration of the Industrial Technology Research Institute – Taipei, Taiwan, 1993 July 6-7; 1045 (Box 40, Folder 61)
    - "La Regione Giuliano- Dalmata – Una Veduta della sua storia e del Suo Futuro" – Al Convegno Internazionale Dell Associazione – New York, 1993 September 5; 1052 (Box 40, Folder 62)
    - "Bridge Between American and Italian Engineering Education & Research" – Seminar – Polytechnic University, 1993 September 21; 1053 (Box 40, Folder 63)
    - "The Role of University, Industry and International Collaboration" – Seminar on Changing Characteristics of Science and Technology in International Development – National Research Council - Washington D.C., 1993 September 27; 1054 (Box 40, Folder 64)
    - "The Role of Universities in Charting a Path" – Seminar on Changing Characteristics of Science and Technology in International Development – National Research Council – Washington, DC, 1993 October 2; 1055 (Box 40, Folder 65)
    - "Thoughts on the Future of Science and Engineering" – Commencement Address, Illinois Institute of Technology, 1993 December 19; 1854 (Box 40, Folder 66)
    - "The Future of Engineering" – Polytechnic University at Westchester, 1994 February; 1057 (Box 40, Folder 67)
    - Material for possible use in speeches, 1978-1989; 1061 (Box 40, Folder 68)
    - Commencement, undated; 7161 (Box 40, Folder 69)
    - "Computer and Soviet Society" – New School for Social Research, Undated; 1855 (Box 40, Folder 70)
    - "How Science and Engineering Operate", Undated; 1058 (Box 40, Folder 71)
    - Overhead Projection Slides – Lectures, Undated; 1060 (Box 40, Folder 72)
  - Subseries B: Symposia, 2081
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 1, 1973-1975; 2083 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 2, 1973-1975; 2084 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 3, 1973-1975; 2085 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 4, 1973-1975; 2086 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 5, 1973-1975; 2087 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 6, 1973-1975; 2088 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 7, 1973-1975; 2089 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 8, 1973-1975; 2090 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 9, 1973-1975; 2091 (Box 41, Folder 9)